Guide to the Forrest Lee Dimmick papers, 1911-1968
Dimmick, Forrest Lee papers, 1911-1968
- Series III. CAT (Color Aptitude Test) and C.I.E. (Commission International Éclairage) research items
  In 1940 the Inter-Society Color Council began the development of its color aptitude test. At the request of professional and industrial groups, the ISCC established a subcommittee, problem 10, to develop a test that would measure an operator's capability to make valid and reliable judgemnts of the likeness and difference of color samples. Dimmick was the co-chairman of this committee and results about the findings of the subcommittee have appeared in various numbers of the newsletter.
  - Professional tools
    Color plates, slides, negatives which were used for research for CAT
    - 26 - 2" colored glass plates (some damaged). In black case. (Box 3, 1)
    - Black and white slides and negatives (Box 3, 2)
    - 2 color negatives. (Box 3, 3)
    - 6 color guides. (Box 3, 4)
    - color swatch book (Box 3, 5)
    - color swatch book. (NU Color scale is in card file 6) (Box 3, 6)
    - D & H Color rule (Box 3, 7)
    - Various color swatches used to demonstrate color standards (Box 3, 8)
    - 12" x 12" board demonstrating the gray color scale. (Box 3, 9)
    - Vinyl color samples demonstrating color hues (Box 3, 10, 11, 12)
    - Lakowski, R. and McDermot, A. A Bibliography on Colour. Square Publishers Ltd., Edinburgh, 1966. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Flyers for various psychological and physiological testing apparati. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Bibliography on cards. (alphabetical) (Box 4, 4)
    - Bibliography file on cards. (subject) (Box 5, 5)
    - NU Color scale (color swatches). (Box 6, 6)
  - Test Charts and results.
    - Several versions of the paper Color Specifications Based on Just Noticeable Differences of Hue. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Computer Print-Out Sheet. (Box 7, 2)
    - Charts. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Test results obtained November 1934. (Color Measurement lab. M.I.T.) (Box 7, 4 & 5)
    - Test results, July-August 1964. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Test results, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Test results on color, 1961-1962. (Box 7, 8)
    - Test results with notes, 1963. (Box 7, 9)
    - Test results, Original Title Munsell Specifications--working copies. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Test results, Tetrahedral Sampling Munsell Value 1/ (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Test results, notes, papers. Folder original labelled: Dimensions of Color. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Test results, with gray color swatches (originally labelled: Reflectance Curves for Gray Series). (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - One program, correspondence, paper in this folder labelled: "Metamers." (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Test results, scales. Comparison of Munsell, C.I.E. and Equal Color Scale (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - C.I.E. Blanks. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - The folder concerns only the Color Aptitude Test (CAT). (Provenance conserved. Content of folders transferred as is.) Scores of Individuals. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Color Aptitude Test. Analysis of Data. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Color Aptitude Test. Repeating Testing. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Color Aptitude Test. Charts and Calculations. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Color Aptitude Test. Variations in Sensitivity to Color. Research Notes. (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Several versions of Specifications and Calibration of the 1953 Edition of the ISCC Color Aptitude Test. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Color Aptitude Test. Committee Items. Production of: Report on: (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Quellette, L.A.Age Differences in Color Discrimination. MA Dissertation, Fordham U. 1955. (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Williams, D. H. An Investigation of Possible Methods for Predicting Success in Color Discrimination for the Paint Industry. MA Dissertation, Western Reserve U. 1949. (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Awards
    - Award for his research at the Naval Medical research Laboratory (1947-1963). (Box 7)
    - Armin J. Bruening Award for his research in the field of applied color psychology. (Box 7)
- Series IV: Inter-Society Color Council
  - Newsletters
    - Inter-Society Color Council Newsletters. October 16, 1933, #1-November1944, #56. (Box 8)
    - Inter-Society Color Council Newsletters. January 1945, #57-September 1954, #114. (Box 9)
    - Inter-Society Color Council Newsletters. November 1954, #115-May-June 1967, #188. (Box 10)
  - Various material relating to ISCC, including a bibliography and color chart.
    - Goodlove, I. H., Bibliography on Color. ISCC, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Reports prepared for the ISCC by various memers of the Committee. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Color Aptitude Test 1953 edition and 1964 edition. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Announcements for meetings, notes, discussions, symposia. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - ISCC constitution and by-laws. Membership list and list of member societies. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - ISCC-NBS Color-Name Charts Illustrated with Centroid colors. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Reports and reprints on CAT. (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Series V: Optical Society of America (OSA)
  - Reports on Uniform Color Scales.
    - Reports on Uniform Color Scale, 1955-1967. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Reports on Uniform Color Scale, 1954-1962. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Reports on Uniform Color Scale, 1964-1966. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence relating to the above folder 1-3, 1947-1964. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Paper by Deane B. Judd with annotations and correspondence relating to same. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Department of Commerce. National Bureau of Standards--Uniform Color Scale. 1954-1962.
    - National Academy of Sciences--National Research Council. NRC Committee on Vision. (1965) (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Application and Notes for NSF Grant, 1967. (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Series VI: Personal Activities, 1963-1968
  - Research and correspondence for writing a biography of Edward Bradford Titchener.
    - Genealogical Research (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with three Titchener children, 1967. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Edwin G. Boring, several articles and typewritten notes. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Handwritten notes by Dimmick, clippings, copies of letters to Titchener. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with the department of Oral History, Cornell, H. P. Weld and C. A. larson. A transcript and working copies of a tape (January 1967) with Weld. Original tape 2862/tr.257 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Copies of 2 letters by Titchener and student and class lists with Titchener's name, all from Leipsig. (10 pp.) (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Professional meetings, 1966-1968, in Dresden, Germany. (Includes correspondence and photos)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1968. Photos, postcards, calling cards. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Annotated copies of 'Application of the Psychometic System of Color Specification to the Munsell Book of Color and to the Problems of Metamerism.' One German copy. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Professional meetings in Sweden, 1966. (Includes correspondence.)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1967. (Includes calling cards and photos.) (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Meeting in Stockholm, 1966. (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Series VII: Correspondence, 1929-1967
  - Correspondence, 1929-1954. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Corresondence, 1964-1965. (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-Dec. 1966. (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Corresondence, Feb.-Dec. 1967. (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Series VIII: Personal memorabilia
  - Dimmick's Valedictory at Waterloo High School, June 22, 1911. (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Paper on telepathy and newspaper clipping, August 4, 1921. (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Items concerning his retirement. (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Two letters concerning his family research. (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Diplomas and certificates of merit. (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Photos.
    - 1 photo - First Co. of Psychologists, 1918. Company F Recruit Section, Hopital Battalion 14, Camp Greenleaf, Ft. Oglethorpe, Ga. Dimmick identified. (Box 13, 1)
    - 1 pohoto - W. Wundt etching by Felix Pfeifer, 1905. (Box 13, 2)
    - 1 photo - 'Experimentalists! Meetnig Harvard (?) probably 1922-23. Many people are identified, i.e. Weld, Boring, Dimmick, Pratt, et al. (Box 13, 3)
    - Cornell Chapter Phi Delta Kappa, 1914-1915. Several people are identified: Dimmick, Boring (Box 13, 4)
    - Photo of Conference for Visual Research Specialists. Dimmick and others are identified. (Box 13, 5)
    - 1 group photo of possibly a psychologists' meeting, c. 1920. (Box 13, 6)
    - 5 unidentified photos, probably all taken at the U.S. Naval Medical Research Laboratory (Box 13, 7)
    - 3 photos which were probably taken when he received the award for his work in color research. Besides Dimmick, nobody can be identified. (Box 13, 8)
- Series IX: Mrs. Claire Comstock Dimmick, Ph.D. '20
  - 1 letter by Titchener, Jan. 21, 1921, written to Claire Comstock. (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - 2 book reviews published in the American Journal of Psychology. (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - 1 article (reprint) Comstock, Claire & Kittredge, Helen. An Experimental Study of children as Observers, Am. J. Psychol. April 1922, pp. 161-177. (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - The Book of the Class Nineteen Hundred and Twelve. Smith College, 1912. Also two unidentified photos. (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - 1 copy "Commencement Week Smith College, June 1-18, 1912." (Box 12, Folder 29)
- Series X: Additional material
  - Recording of a conversation with Weld in Florida, January 1967; tr.257
  - 1944 Cornell Ph.D Diploma and U.S. Naval Medical Research Laboratory Sub Base commendation. (Map-case W-10)